<molgenis name="org.molgenis">
	<module name="core">
		<description>Generic entities you can use as the starting point of
			your model.</description>
		<entity name="Identifiable" abstract="true" system="true">
			<description>This interface assigns an automatic 'id' field to every
				object.</description>
			<field name="id" type="autoid" description="automatically generated id" />
		</entity>
		<entity name="Nameable" abstract="true" 
			implements="Identifiable">
			<description>This interface extends Identifiable with a unique 'name'
				field. The name length can be stored in one byte. (Java has signed
				integers) The name is by itself not unique, this should be enforced
				within a certain context. For example, unique(name, study) to make
				the name unique within one single study. The NameableDecorator
				ensures that names don't lead to problems in R and other script
				environments.</description>
			<field name="name" length="127" type="varchar" description="human-readable name." />
		</entity>
		<entity name="Describable" abstract="true" system="true">
			<description>This interface adds a description field to all entities
				the implement it.</description>
			<field name="description" type="text" nillable="true"
				description="description field" />
		</entity>
		<entity name="OntologyTerm" xref_label="name" implements="Nameable">
			<description>
				OntologyTerm defines a single entry (term) from an ontology or a
				controlled vocabulary (defined by Ontology). The name is the
				ontology term which is unique within an ontology source, such as
				[examples here]. Other data entities can reference to this
				OntologyTerm to harmonize naming of concepts. Each term should have
				a local, unique label within the Investigation. If no suitable
				ontology term exists then one can define new terms locally (in which
				case there is no formal accession for the term limiting its use for
				cross-Investigation queries). In those cases the local name should
				be repeated in both term and termAccession. Maps to
				FuGE::OntologyIndividual; in MAGE-TAB there is no separate entity to
				model terms.
				<br />
				Optionally a local controlled vocabulary or ontology can be defined,
				for example to represent 'Codelists' often used in questionaires.
				Note: this is not a InvestigationElement because of the additional
				xref_label and unique constraint.This class defines a single entry
				from an ontology or a controlled vocabulary.
				<br />
				If it is a simple controlled vocabulary, there may be no formal
				accession for the term. In these cases the local name should be
				repeated in both term and termAccession. If the term has a value,
				the OntologyTerm will have a single DataProperty whose value was the
				value for the property. For instance, for an OntologyIndividual
				based on the MO ontology the attributes might be: The term would be
				what is usually called the local name in the Ontology, for instance
				'Age'; The termAccession could be
				'http://mged.sourceforge.net/ontologies/MGEDOntology.owl#Age' or a
				an arbitrary accession if one exists; The identifier is a unique
				identifier for individuals in the scope of the FuGE instance; The
				inherited name attribute should not be used; The ontologyURI of
				OntologySource could be
				'http://mged.sourceforge.net/ontologies/MGEDOntology.owl&quot;. The
				OntologyTerm subclasses are instances of Ontology classes and
				properties, not the actual terms themselves. An OntologyIndividual,
				if based on an existing Ontology, can be considered a statement that
				can be validated against the referenced ontology. The subclasses and
				their associations are based on the Ontology Definition Model,
				ad/2005-04-13, submitted to the OMG as a response to RFP
				ad/2003-03-40, Copyright 2005 DSTC Pty Ltd. Copyright 2005 IBM
				Copyright 2005 Sandpiper Software, Inc under the standard OMG
				license terms. 
			</description>
			<field auto="false" name="ontology" type="xref" nillable="true"
				description="(Optional) The source ontology or controlled vocabulary list that ontology terms have been obtained from."
				xref_entity="Ontology" />
			<field nillable="true" auto="false" name="termAccession" type="varchar"
				description="(Optional) The accession number assigned to the ontology term in its source ontology. If empty it is assumed to be a locally defined term. " />
			<field nillable="true" auto="false" name="definition" type="string"
				description="(Optional) The definition of the term." />
			<unique fields="ontology,termAccession"
				description="The term accession is unique within an Ontology" />
			<field nillable="true" auto="false" name="termPath" type="varchar"
				length="1024"
				description="EXTENSION. The Ontology Lookup Service path that contains this term." />
			<unique fields="ontology,name" description="ADDITION: Name is unique within its type " />
		</entity>
		<entity name="Ontology" implements="Nameable" xref_label="name">
			<description> Ontology defines a reference to a an ontology or
				controlled vocabulary from which well-defined and stable (ontology)
				terms can be obtained. Each Ontology should have a unique name, for
				instance: Gene Ontology, Mammalian Phenotype, Human Phenotype
				Ontology, Unified Medical Language System, Medical Subject Headings,
				etc. Also a abbreviation is required, for instance: GO, MP, HPO,
				UMLS, MeSH, etc. Use of existing ontologies/vocabularies is
				recommended to harmonize phenotypic feature and value descriptions.
				But one can also create a 'local' Ontology. The Ontology class maps
				to FuGE::Ontology, MAGE-TAB::TermSourceREF.</description>
			<field auto="false" name="ontologyAccession" type="string"
				nillable="true"
				description="A identifier that uniquely identifies the ontology (typically an acronym). E.g. GO, MeSH, HPO." />
			<field nillable="true" auto="false" name="ontologyURI" type="hyperlink"
				description="(Optional) A URI that references the location of the ontology." />
			<unique fields="name" description="Name is unique within its type " />
		</entity>
		<entity name="MolgenisEntity" system="true" implements="Identifiable" xref_label="className" >
			<description>Referenceable catalog of entity names, menus, forms and
				plugins.</description>
			<field name="name" description="Name of the entity" />
			<field name="type_" description="Type of the entity" />
			<field name="className" unique="true" description="Full name of the entity" />
			<unique fields="name,type_" />
		</entity>
	</module>
</molgenis>